Edward Livingston Papers, 1683-1877 (bulk 1764-1836 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 4: Auguste Davezac (1780-1851), brother of Louise Livingston, 1822-1851; 1 box
  - Correspondence, 1822-1849; portion of 1 box
    - Viardot, Louis, 1800-1883, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Unidentified, 1849; 1 folder (Folder 18)
  - Writings and Speeches, 1824; 1 folder (Folder 19)
  - Diplomatic Service Documents, 1829-1845; 1 folder (Folder 20)
  - Papers Relating to Estate, 1851; 1 folder (Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1824-1843; 1 folder (Folder 22)
- Series 5: Lewis Livingston (1798-1821), son of Edward and Mary McEvers Livingston, 1814-1822; 2 boxes
  Contains correspondence; a school notebook that includes notes on trigonometry, surveyor's math and surveying, business mathmatics, and the calculation of eclipses; some sketches and drawings attributed to Lewis by John Ross Delafield; accounts, receipts and bills of sale; and some miscellaneous papers including power of attorney, a military commission, a certificate to practice law, and his obituary. Correspondents include Andrew Jackson, William Smith of Canada, and family members. Note: This archivist thinks that at least some of the sketches and drawings are, in fact, not by Lewis Livingston. Both of Lewis's sisters Julia and Coralie are artists by their own admission (see Edward Livingston's Correspondence: Family series (A.2)). Some of these items may have been drawn by either of them.
  Note: for papers of Mary McEvers Livingston, Edward Livingston's first wife, see Paper of Others
  - Correspondence, 1814-1820; portion of 1 box
    - Garretson, Catherine, 1752-1849 (Aunt), 1814; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845, 1815-1820; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Livingston, Julia, 1794-1814 (Sister), undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Livingston, Robert Montgomery, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Smith, William, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - School Notebook, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Sketches and Drawings (oversized), undated; 1 box
    (attributed to Lewis Livingston by John Ross Delafield. At least one drawing is probably by Julia Livingston, 1794-1813)
  - Accounts, Receipts and Bills of Sale, 1817-1820; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1818-1822; 1 folder (Folder 8)
- Series 6: Janet Montgomery (1743-1828), sister of Edward Livingston, 1764-1852; 1764-1828; 10 boxes
  Consists of the correspondence, financial records, account books, copy books, and miscellaneous papers of Janet Montgomery (1743-1828), sister of Edward Livingston.
  This series is arranged into four subseries: Correspondence, Financial Records, Account Books/Copy Books, and Miscellaneous Papers.
  - Subseries 6A: Correspondence, 1764-1828; 4 boxes
    Frequent correspondents include niece Cora Livingston Barton, DeWitt Clinton, agent John Cox, Jr., Horatio Gates, nephew Charles Jones, nephew Lewis Livingston, sister-in-law Louise Livingston, brother Robert R. Livingston, husband Richard Montgomery, whose letters where penned on the march to Quebec, Catherine Noble, sister-in-law Lady Sarah Ranelagh, and Mercy Otis Warren. Other correspondents include members of the Livingston, Montgomery, and Jones families, tenants, and prominent persons such as Jefferson, Lafayette, and James Monroe. Domestic and financial matters, politics, Richard Montgomery's death and the eventual return of his remains are among the topics discussed.
    Box 105, folder 1 is restricted. Consult curator for access.
    - Alexander, Catherine Livingston, 1778; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Armstrong, Alida Livingston, 1761-1822 (Sister), 1791-1810; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Armstrong, John Jr. (Nephew), 1825; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Armstrong, Mary (Niece), undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Bailey, Jacob (and Others), 1792; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Ballantyne, Robert, 1812; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Barton, Cora Livingston, 1806-1873 (Niece), 1818-1819; 2 folders (Folder 7-8)
    - Beardslee, Nehemiah, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Bennet, J., undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Browne, A., undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Clement, M., 1784-1790; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Clinton, DeWitt, 1769-1828, 1818-1819; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Close, Mary, 1789; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Clum, "Widow", 1817; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Cockburn, William, 1784; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      Includes survey and estimate of Richard Montgomery's farm, Kingsbridge
    - Constable, Ann, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Cooke, Elizabeth, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Cox, John Jr., 1756-1825, 1791-1822; 11 folders (Folder 19-29)
    - Craig, M.M., 1784; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Croghan, Serena Livingston (Niece), undated; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - Cruseau, Charles, 1798; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Dehart, Cyrus, 1794; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - DuPonceau, Peter, 1760-1844, 1815-1818; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Elliot, Thomas and Oliver, John, undated; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Fletcher, Andrew, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Floy, Michael, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 37)
    - Gage, Mrs., undated; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - Garretson, Catherine Livingston, 1752-1849 (Sister), 1793-1818; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Gates, Horatio, 1728-1806, 1784-1804; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Gebhard, Philip, 1802-1803; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Gordon, C., 1768-1771; 1 folder (Folder 42)
    - Greene, Clark, 1794; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - Gregory, Abija, 1799; 1 folder (Folder 44)
    - Griffin, C., undated; 1 folder (Folder 45)
    - Hagan, Thomas, undated; 1 folder (Folder 46)
    - Halkett, 1821; 1 folder (Folder 47)
    - Hall, Abel, 1799; 1 folder (Folder 48)
    - Hamilton, James, 1777; 1 folder (Folder 49)
    - Harrison, John, 1823; 1 folder (Folder 50)
    - Haslen, H., 1819; 1 folder (Folder 51)
    - Hawkins, Samuel, 1810; 1 folder (Folder 52)
    - Hyde, John Wilkes, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 53)
    - Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826, 1798; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Jones, Catherine, 1814; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Jones, Charles (Nephew), 1788-1794; 5 folders (Folder 3-7)
    - Jones, M., 1821; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Jones, Sophia, circa 1789; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Jones, William, -1812 (Nephew), 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Kerby, Thomas Norbury, 1810; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Kinsey, Mary, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Lafayette, Marquis de, 1757-1834, 1786-1816; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Lansing, John, 1754-1829, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Latham, Thomas, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Lawrence, Effingham, 1803-1817; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Lawrence, William Effingham, 1809; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Lear, Tobias, 1762-1816, 1801; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Lenox, Robert, 1821; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Lewis, Morgan, 1754-1844 (Brother-in-Law), 1799; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Livingston and Rudd, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Livingston, Cornelia Louisiana, 1802-1830 (Niece), undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Livingston, Edward (Nephew), 1821-1823; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Livingston, Edward P., 1779-1843 (Cousin, Nephew-in-Law), 1819-1822; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Livingston, Elizabeth S. (Niece), 1802; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - Livingston, Joanna, 1759-1829 (Sister), 1790; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Livingston, John of Oak Hill, 1750-1822, 1811; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Livingston, John R., 1755-1851 (Brother), 1784-1826; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - Livingston, John S. (Mr and Mrs), undated; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Livingston, Lewis, 1798-1822 (Nephew), 1813-1821; 5 folders (Folder 30-34)
    - Livingston, Louise, 1781-1860 (Sister-in-Law), 1822-1825; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Livingston, Margaret Beekman, 1724-1800 (Mother), 1788-1790; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Livingston, Mary McEvers, -1801 (Sister-in-Law), 1790-1798; 1 folder (Folder 37)
    - Livingston, Mary Stevens, 1752-1814, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - Livingston, Maturin, 1769-1847, 1809-1822; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Livingston, Richard Montgomery (Nephew), 1818-1821; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Livingston, Robert, 1688-1775 (Grandfather), 1764-1772; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Livingston, Robert L., undated; 1 folder (Folder 42)
    - Livingston, Robert Montgomery, 1790-1838 (Nephew), undated; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - Livingston, Robert R., 1718-1775 (Father), 1 folder (Folder 44)
    - Livingston, Robert R. (Chancellor), 1746-1813 (Brother), circa 1760-1806; 6 folders (Folder 45-50)
    - Losing, George, 1794; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Mabie, Jacob, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Mallet, M., 1808-1824; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Mancius, Catherine and GW, 1816-1820; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - McEvers, Charles, 1816-1822; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - McEvers, G.L., undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - McEvers, Gulian, 1793-1802; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - McWilliams, James, 1804; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Meetr, Raymond, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Menzies, Robert, 1813; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Monroe, James, 1758-1831, 1800-1818; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Montgomery, Alexander (Brother-in-Law), 1791; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Montgomery, Anna Maria, 1793-1819; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Montgomery, Catherine, 1793; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Montgomery, Eleanora, 1790-1802; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Montgomery, F., circa 1789-1790; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Montgomery, John (Brother-in-Law), 1785-1790; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Montgomery, Richard, 1736-1775 (Husband), 5 folders (Folder 18-22)
      Folders 18-21 contain fragile items. Photocopying not advised. Photocopies in folder 22.
    - Montgomery, Robert (Robin), 1789-1816; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Montgomery, Sophie, 1791; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Montgomery, William, 1778; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - More, John T., 1821; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Newenham, Edward, 1789-1794; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Newman, W.E., 1817; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - Niemcewicz, Susan Ursin, 1755-1833, 1813; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Noble, Catherine, 1785-1794; 2 folders (Folder 30-31)
    - Outwater, Peter, 1815; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Prevost, G.W., 1808; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Provoost, Maria, 1790; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Ranelagh, Lord, 1784; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Ranelagh, Sarah, Lady (Sister-in-Law), 1777-1790; 17 folders (Folder 36-42)
    - Ranelagh, Sarah, Lady (Sister-in-Law), 1777-1790; 17 folders (Folder 1-10)
    - Remsen, Henry, 1803-1813; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Russell, William, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Schell, Christian, 1820-1821; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Schuyler, Phillip, 1820; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Scott, Robert, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Selkirk, J., 1821; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Sherbrooke, Sir John Coape, 1764-1830, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Slosson, William, 1808-1811; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Smith, C., 1765; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Smith, William, 1816-1819; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Sofir, Peleg, 1828; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Stewart, D., undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Street, R.S., 1810-1813; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Tenants of Rhinebeck, 1795; 1 folder (Folder 24)
      Alternate title: Subscribers, Freeholders, and Inhabitants of Rhinebeck
    - Temple, Elizabeth, 1800-1806; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - Tenants of Delaware County, 1812; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Ternant, 1794-1803; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Thomson, Walter, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - Tillon, Francis R., 1820; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Tillotson, Emily C., 1820-1821; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Tillotson, Margaret, 1749-1823 (Sister), 1790-1815; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - Tillotson, R. (Nephew), 1822; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Tillotson, Thomas, 1752-1832 (Brother-in-Law), 1822; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Van Cortlandt, James, 1776; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Van Keuren, Garret, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Van Ness, Anne, undated; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Van Ness, G.B., 1799; 1 folder (Folder 37)
    - Van Ness, Jacob, 1812-1821; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - Vander Weyden, 1821; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Vogelsang, Peter, 1819-1821; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Warren, Henry, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Warren, Mercy Otis, 1728-1814, 1776-1792; 2 folders (Folder 42-43)
    - Watson, Elkanah, 1758-1842, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 44)
    - Wheeler, John, undated; 1 folder (Folder 45)
    - Unidentified - JM to Others, undated; 1 folder (Folder 46)
    - Unidentified - to JM, undated; 1 folder (Folder 47)
  - Subseries 6B: Financial Records, 1772-1833; 3 boxes
    Contains general financial records, including accounts, receipts, bills of sale, rent accounts and receipts. The remainder of the series is comprised of several folders of notes, bonds and small notebooks.
    - Accounts: General, 1772-1833; 1772-1828; 3 boxes
      Some tax records in this series. There are also tax receipts and other tax records in the landholdings series.
      - Accounts: General, 1772; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Accounts: General, 1774; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Accounts: General, 1776; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Accounts: General, 1779; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Accounts: General, 1780; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Accounts: General, 1781; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Accounts: General, 1782; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Accounts: General, 1783; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Accounts: General, 1784; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Accounts: General, 1785; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Accounts: General, 1786; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Accounts: General, 1787; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Accounts: General, 1788; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Accounts: General, 1789; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Accounts: General, 1790; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Accounts: General, 1791; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Accounts: General, 1792; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Accounts: General, 1793; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Accounts: General, 1794; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - Accounts: General, 1795; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      - Accounts: General, 1796; 1 folder (Folder 21)
      - Accounts: General, 1797; 1 folder (Folder 22)
      - Accounts: General, 1798; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      - Accounts: General, 1799; 1 folder (Folder 24)
      - Accounts: General, 1800; 1 folder (Folder 25)
      - Accounts: General, 1801; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      - Accounts: General, 1802; 1 folder (Folder 27)
      - Accounts: General, 1803; 1 folder (Folder 28)
      - Accounts: General, 1804; 1 folder (Folder 29)
      - Accounts: General, 1805; 1 folder (Folder 30)
      - Accounts: General, 1806; 1 folder (Folder 31)
      - Accounts: General, 1807; 1 folder (Folder 32)
      - Accounts: General, 1808; 1 folder (Folder 33)
      - Accounts: General, 1809; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Accounts: General, 1810; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Accounts: General, 1811; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Accounts: General, 1812; 1 folder (Folder 4-5)
      - Accounts: General, 1813; 1 folder (Folder 6-7)
      - Accounts: General, 1814; 1 folder (Folder 8-9)
      - Accounts: General, 1815; 1 folder (Folder 10-11)
      - Accounts: General, 1816; 1 folder (Folder 12-13)
      - Accounts: General, 1817; 1 folder (Folder 14-15)
      - Accounts: General, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Accounts: General, 1819; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Accounts: General, 1820; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Accounts: General, 1821; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Accounts: General, 1822; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Accounts: General, 1823; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Accounts: General, 1824; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Accounts: General, 1825; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Accounts: General, 1826; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Accounts: General, 1827; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Accounts: General (Post-humous), 1828-1833; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Accounts: General, undated; 2 folders (Folder 12-13)
      - Accounts: General: 3rd Party, 1804-1828; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Accounts: General: Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Notes and Bonds, 1783-1828; portion of 1 box
      - Notes and Inventory, 1793-1825; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Notes to John Cox, Jr, 1795-1825; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Bonds Payable, 1790-1827; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Bonds Receivable, 1794-1828; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Small Notebooks, 1786-1828; 2 folders (Folder 20-21)
  - Subseries 6C: Account Books/Copy Books, 1773-1820; 2 boxes
    Contains four books used for various purposes. Includes general financial accounts, rent accounts, hand-copied letters, poetry, and daily finances. Some accounts are carried over from Janet's grandfather, Henry Beekman's records.
    Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
    - Account Book/Copy Book, 1773-1787; 1 item
    - Account Book (oversized), circa 1780-1820; 1 box
    - Accounts - Beekman Pct, 1787-1790; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Daybook, 1814-1817; 1 item
  - Subseries 6D: Miscellaneous Papers, 1788-1852; 1788-1828; 1 box
    Includes memoirs written by Janet Montgomery, wills, inventories, legal papers, indentured servant and slaveholder documents, miscellaneous correspondence of Janet's overseer and agent, and a newspaper clipping describing the return of Richard Montgomery's remains from Quebec.
    - Memoirs, 1818; portion of 1 box
      - Account of Janet Montgomery's Ancestors and Family, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Account of Richard Montgomery, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Account of a Bond, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Transcript of a Portion of Janet Montgomery's Memoirs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Wills, 1808-1852; 1808-1825; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Inventories, 1828; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Legal Documents, 1789-1827; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Indentures of Servants and Slaveholder Documents, 1788-1817; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Letters to Andrew Vosburgh, 1825-1826; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence of Garrett Van Keuren, 1826-1827; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Account Describing the Return of Richard Montgomery's Remains, 1818; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
- Series 7: Richard Montgomery (1738-1775), husband of Janet Montgomery, 1761-1813; 1761-1787; 1 box
  Contains several pieces of correspondence (arranged alphabetically), two folders of financial records, including receipts, bills and estate accounts, and miscellaneous papers, including a marriage license, wills, inventory of effects at death, and several legal documents. Correspondents include father-in-law Robert R. Livingston and James Rivington.
  - Correspondence, 1773-1775; portion of 1 box
    - Livingston, Robert R., 1718-1775 (Father-in-Law), 1773; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Ranelagh, Sarah, Lady (Sister), circa 1774; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Rivington, James, 1724-1802, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Wallace, M., 1773; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Unidentified Friend from Ireland, circa 1774-1775; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Financial Records, 1761-1781; 1 folder
    - Accounts, Receipts and Bills of Sale to 1775, 1761-1775; 2 folders (Folder 6-7)
    - Estate Accounts and Related Documents, 1774-1781; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1773-1813; 1773-1787; portion of 1 box
    (Chrono)
    - Marriage License, 1773; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Will, 1775-1813; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Inventory of Personal Effects at Death, 1776; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Memorandum re: Casualties and Expenses at Quebec, 1776; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Lord and Lady Ranelagh's Power of Attorney Concerning Their Inheritance, 1778; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Court Case Relative to Settlement of Estate, 1787; 1 folder (Folder 14)
- Series 8: William Jones (circa 1778-circa 1813), nephew of Richard Montgomery, 1796-1816; 1 box
  Contains correspondence with his family in Ireland, accounts, receipts and bills of sale, and miscellaneous papers, including a contract for the purchase of the contents of a house.
  This series is arranged into three subseries: Correspondence, Accounts, Receipts and Bills of Sale, and Miscellaneous Papers.
  - Correspondence, 1796-1815; portion of 1 box
    - Hamilton, William V., 1802; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Jones, Sarah (Sister), 1801-1815; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Lawrence, Effingham (and Son), 1803-1806; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Molesworth, Viscount and Mary, 1796-1811; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Ranelagh, Lady Sarah (Mother), 1801-1811; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Ranelagh, Thomas, 1801-1806; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Accounts, Receipts and Bills of Sale, 1798-1816; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Contract for Purcahse of the Contents of a House, 1807; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Photocopy of 1952 Documents Verifying William Jones' Will, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
- Series 9: Margaret Beekman Livingston (1724-1800) and Robert R. Livingston(1718-1775), parents of Edward Livingston, 1735-1833; 13 boxes
  Consists of the papers of Margaret Beekman Livingston (1724-1800) and Robert R. Livingston(1718-1775), parents of Edward Livingston, largely comprised of correspondence and financial records, as well as miscellaneous papers.
  The Livingstons each have their own series, then a joint one.
  - Subseries 9A: Margaret Beekman Livingston (1724-1800), 1735-1833; 1755-1811; 7 boxes
    Consists of the papers of Margaret Beekman Livingston (1724-1800), including correspondence, financial records, miscellaneous papers, and papers related to William and James Cockburn.
    - Correspondence, 1755-1799; 1 box
      The general correspondence includes tenants, tradesmen, business connections, and clergyman F. Adrian Van der Kemp. Many of the items in the latter two groups were found among agent John Cox, Jr's. papers. (See series XIII. John Cox, Jr.)
      Arranged in three groups: family (arranged alphabetically), with estate agents John Cox, Jr. and William Cockburn (arranged chronologically for each agent), and general (arranged alphabetically).
      - Family, 1755-1799; portion of 1 box
        - Garrettson, Catherine Livingston, 1752-1849 (Daughter), 1798; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Garrettson, Freeborn, 1752-1827 (Son-in-Law), 1789; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Livingston, Margaret Beekman (Granddaughter), 1799; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Livingston, Robert Gilbert, 1783; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Livingston, Robert R., Judge, 1718-1775 (Husband), 1755; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Livingston, Robert R., the Chancellor, 1746-1813 (Son), 1788; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Tillotson, Thomas, 1752-1832, 1790; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Unidentified Addressees, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - With Estate Agents John Cox, Jr. and Will Cockburn, 1782-1799; portion of 1 box
        - William Cockburn, d. 1804, 1782-1791; 1 folder (Folder 9)
          (chrono)
        - John Cox, Jr., 1756-1825, 1791-1799; 9 folders (Folder 10-18)
      - General, 1766-1798; portion of 1 box
        - Ambler, Mary, 1795; 1 folder (Folder 19)
        - Baker, Samuel, 1781; 1 folder (Folder 20)
        - Brisbane, William, 1791; 1 folder (Folder 21)
        - Cutting, 1798; 1 folder (Folder 22)
        - Davis, Isaac, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
        - Davis, John, 1798; 1 folder (Folder 24)
        - Davis, Richard, 1792; 1 folder (Folder 25)
        - DeLeGarde, 1784-1785; 1 folder (Folder 26)
        - Elmendorf, Conradt C., 1786; 1 folder (Folder 27)
        - Frelich, Henry, 1789; 1 folder (Folder 28)
        - Gellet, Richard, 1784; 1 folder (Folder 29)
        - Gregory, Uriah M., 1793; 1 folder (Folder 30)
        - Ketchum, Micha, 1791; 1 folder (Folder 31)
        - Lott, Abraham, 1790; 1 folder (Folder 32)
        - Millar, Thomas, 1798; 1 folder (Folder 33)
        - More, Jonathan, 1776-1791; 1 folder (Folder 34)
        - Potter, Samuel and Prudence, 1786-1791; 1 folder (Folder 35)
        - Progue, George, 1793; 1 folder (Folder 36)